George Clary Papers
Connecticut Historical Society
George Clary Papers.
1843-1881
Connecticut Historical Society, Hartford, Connecticut
Clary, George
0.6 linear foot (2 boxes)
Collection consists of his correspondence, diaries, papers and essays, papers of his family and transcriptions of some of his papers.
Biographical Sketch
George Clary was born in Cornish, New Hampshire in 1829, the son of Rev. Joseph and Lucy Clary. Following his 1852 graduation from Dartmouth College, Clary studied with physicians in Thetford, New Hampshire and Hartford, Connecticut while also working as a clerk in a drug store. He attended the Yale School of Medicine, graduating in 1857. During the Civil War he served as surgeon in the Thirteenth Regiment of Connecticut Volunteers.
Clary married Mary Rebecca Dorrance in 1867 and settled in New Britain, Connecticut. He was a member of the medical societies of Connecticut, New Britain and Hartford and one of the founders of the New Britain Y. M. C. A. He died on December 30, 1916. A copy of his obituary is available in the Mary Morris Obituary Scrapbooks at the Connecticut Historical Society.
Scope and Content
Collection consists largely of correspondence with his family, his diaries, his writings and transcriptions of selected portions of these materials.
Materials are organized into 6 series, based on arrangement by the donor, and are arranged chronologically within each series.
Series I: Correspondence consists of letters written from George Clary to his family.
Series II: Diaries were written while Clary was a physician in New Britain, Connecticut and a surgeon in the Thirteenth Regiment of Connecticut Volunteers.
Series III: Papers consists of notes, receipts and general orders.
Series IV: Writings comprises essays on religious, philosophical and historical topics, mostly written while a student.
Series V: Family papers contains correspondence, mostly of George's sister Eliza.
Series VI: Typed transcriptions are of selected portions of George Clary's papers
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions on access to the collection.
Accruals
The collection is open, additional material is not expected.
Subject Headings
Personal Names
Clary, George.
Corporate Names
Connecticut Infantry --13th Regiment.
Subjects
African Americans --Social conditions.
Geographic Names
Hartford (Conn.) --History --Sources.; United States --Politics and government --1849-1877.; United States --History --Civil War, 1861-1865.
Contents:
- I. Correspondence
  - Letters from George Clary, mostly to his brother Timothy., 1854-1859 (Box 1, Folder A)
  - Letters from George Clary to his brother Timothy and his sister Eliza., 1860-1861 (Box 1, Folder B)
  - Letters from George Clary to his family while serving as a surgeon in the Civil War., 1862 (Box 1, Folder C)
  - Letters from George Clary to his brothers and sisters while serving as a surgeon in the Civil War., 1863 January - July (Box 1, Folder D)
  - Letters from George Clary to his brothers and sisters while serving as surgeon in the Civil War., 1863 August - December (Box 1, Folder E)
  - Letters from George Clary to his brothers and sisters while serving as surgeon in the Civil War., 1864 (Box 1, Folder F)
  - Letters from George Clary mostly to his sister Eliza while serving as surgeon in the Civil War., 1865 January - April (Box 1, Folder G)
  - Letters from George Clary to his brothers and sisters while serving as surgeon in the Civil War., 1865 May - December (Box 1, Folder H)
  - Letters from George Clary to his brothers and sisters., 1866, 1881 (Box 1, Folder I)
- II. Diaries
  - Diaries of George Clary, 1858-1862 (Box 1, Folder J)
  - Diaries of George Clary, 1863-1865 (Box 1, Folder K)
- III. Papers
  - Papers of George Clary., 1851-1866 (Box 1, Folder L)
- IV. Writings of George Clary.
  - Essays, 1843-1857 (Box 1, Folder M)
- V. Correspondence of other members of the Clary family
  - Correspondence of other members of the Clary family., 1863-1934 (Box 1, Folder N)
- VI. Typed transcriptions of George Clary's papers
  - Transcription, pages 1-99 (Box 2, Folder O)
  - Transcription, pages 100-199 (Box 2, Folder P)
  - Transcription, pages 200-299 (Box 2, Folder Q)
  - Transcription, pages 300-330 (Box 2, Folder R)